Now, we'll look at techniques for
expanding and enhancing your evaluation
pipeline to give you a comprehensive
testing framework for your LLM apps.
You'll learn how to write evaluations to
detect hallucinations in your application,
run evaluations on multiple data points,
and store evaluation
results for review in CircleCI.
Let's get started.
One common problem with
LLMs is hallucinations,
which happen when the model
provides an answer that is false output.
Hallucinations are a side effect of
current LLMs being next token predictors.
In other words, the
model will always provide
some output that is statistically likely,
but there is no built-in way to ensure
that the model is producing correct output.
In our application, this might
look like the agent creating
a quiz with facts that
are not in our data bank.
For example, we could get an
inaccurate response, like a user asking,
what is the capital of Brazil,
and getting the answer, São Paulo,
and the correct answer is Brasilia.
We could get an irrelevant answer,
again asking what is the capital of Brazil,
and getting the answer the
capital of Canada is Ottawa.
In this case, the statement
that the LLM produced is actually,
factually correct but has nothing to do
with the question that the user is asking.
Or we could get a
contradictory or nonsensical answer,
such as asking what are the major
cities of the USA from largest to smallest,
by population and getting New
York, Los Angeles, Chicago,
and New York one way to detect
hallucinations is to create a model-graded
eval that accepts some ground truth
data that the model should produce
and compare it to the actual output
writing an eval to detect hallucinations
does not guarantee that the
model never hallucinates,
but it is a useful tool to detect
if a prompt does not have guardrails
to prevent the model from guessing
outside of the provided context.
In our application, an
example of a guardrail
might be modifying the prompt to ask the
model to tell the user it can't create
quizzes for subjects not in the quiz bank.
Let's take a look at
putting this into practice.
Before we get started, as always,
we are going to reload our keys so we
can use all of our third-party services.
Let's do that now.
As noted in a previous lesson,
a much more sustainable way to
manage the quiz bank is to put
it in a text file or maybe even
store that data in a database.
In this case, we're using
a text file and loading
that into memory when we want to use it.
If you want to see the contents, you
can print that out in the notebook.
In order to demonstrate
the hallucination detection,
first we will quickly rebuild the quiz
generator that we used previously. So now,
we have the prompt to build
the quiz and the assistant
chain that puts those pieces together.
Now, we'll move on to
creating a model-graded
eval that explicitly
looks for hallucination.
As you can see, for the
purposes of the model-graded eval,
we've put a lot of energy into
expressing how important it is that
quizzes only primary concern
is making sure that only facts
available are used and quizzes
that contain facts outside the
question bank are bad quizzes
and harmful to the student.
Down below, this is highlighted again.
Remember, the quizzes need to only
include facts the assistant is aware of.
It is dangerous to allow made up facts.
And then, similar to our previous evals,
we will output Y if the quiz is correct.
Meaning, it only contains
facts from the question bank,
and N if it contains facts that are
not in the question bank. And now,
we'll define a function to
test our model graded eval
to check what happens
when we have hallucinations.
Using the previously stored quiz bank,
we'll pass it to our new
model-graded eval and check for hallucinations.
In the model-graded eval test
function, we ask for a quiz about books,
which is not included in our quiz bank.
However, in its
attempts to be very helpful,
the LLM has returned a quiz about
books. Our model-graded eval, however,
knows that its job is to
detect quizzes that contain
information that's not in the quiz bank.
And so in this case, we get an N
stating that this is not an acceptable quiz.
What might be causing
these hallucinations?
If you review our prompt, we're telling
the assistant to make the quiz interesting.
This might be a good attribute of a quiz.
Education should be engaging, but it is
causing our model to hallucinate responses.
Fortunately, our evaluation is
detecting these hallucinations,
so we can go back and correct the prompt.
We're going to move on to the next
section, but in our future prompts,
we will remove the piece that
asks for interesting facts.
As your application
grows and changes over time,
you will want to add new functionality.
For our quiz, this might
mean supporting new subjects
or adding facts about existing subjects.
To do this, we can create data sets
of questions where we know how the
model should behave and run tests
on each example in the dataset.
Let's walk through an example of testing
with the dataset with our application code.
We'll update our application code a
bit to prevent the hallucinations.
So far, we've used
evaluations as an automated test suite.
This is a good way to catch
obvious errors and regressions
and to rapidly iterate
on your application.
But when working with AI models,
it is important to get comfortable
manually inspecting and curating data.
Being willing to dig into the data is
something the AI and ML engineers that
we've worked with say is critical
for working effectively in the field.
This is sometimes referred to as
error analysis or performance auditing.
In this example, we'll show
a way to store evaluation
results in CircleCI as an
artifact that you can review
and share with your team to
make sure your application
and test suite are
behaving exactly as you expect.
First, we're gonna
rebuild our evaluator to
provide not just a response or a decision,
but an explanation of why
that decision was made.
As you can see in this
version of the prompt,
we're asking for the
decision and the explanation
to be separated in a particular format.
Here's an example provided as part
of the prompt to ensure that we get
the useful information that we
need back for later human evaluation.
So now, we've rebuilt the chat prompt
template with the new prompt and we're going
to build a data set so that we can run
multiple tests against our new prompt.
As you can see, this test data
set includes multiple different
prompts from the user
or inputs from the user,
along with some expected responses.
Next, we create a function that will
loop through our data set to invoke our
quiz generator and evaluate the
response for each entry in the data set.
Next, we'll make sure that we have
access to all of the functions that we
need in order to generate the report
that we want based on our data set.
Now, we write the wrapper that
you're familiar with to create the
eval chain that we're going to
use through all of our evaluations.
And finally, we take advantage of
some tools from Pandas to create
a data frame across all of our
evaluations and their results,
which will allow us to easily
generate a report. Great. So now,
you can see the formatted table with
multiple results for the different
quizzes that we've generated and
the responses from the grader.
The first was a quiz about
science and the decision is over here.
The decision is yes,
it's an appropriate quiz,
and the quiz only references
information from the question bank.
There's more details included here,
including what specifically is in the quiz
and where it's found in the question bank.
The second one is about geography,
and similarly, the decision is yes,
the quiz only references
information from the question bank. And then,
goes on to explain what
information was taken
from the question bank
to get these questions.
Now, for item three, the quiz
about Italy, the decision is also yes.
And this is interesting
because the quiz does
reference information
from the question bank,
and the facts are from the question bank,
but the model of a quiz about Italy
doesn't specifically map to the categories.
And this is why you want
to have human evaluation
so you can make the
determination of whether
this is the type of quiz
that you would want generated
or whether you want a different result,
which is maybe to say, I don't know
how to generate quizzes about Italy,
which is the actual topic or subject
that's outlined to begin with. So from here,
you could maybe change your
prompt or decide to do something
differently based on the
information that you collected.
And again, involving a human to evaluate
at a high level whether all of the pieces
of the system are working the way you
would expect is a great outcome for us here.
Now, we're going to take
that structure and put
it back into CI so that
it runs in an automated
fashion but creates the
artifact of this report
so that you can review
it on a regular basis.
In order to run it in continuous
integration, we have one additional file,
save eval artifacts, which
generates and stores the output report
that you just saw except as
part of the workflow process.
Here's the content of that file,
which you can look at yourself.
So now, we're going to run our
evals again against that same data set,
but in the continuous integration
pipeline to show what it would be like
to work with this on a regular
basis as we continue to work and grow.
And so, we're going to
trigger the eval report using
the save eval
artifacts file along with our
original application and
the QuizBank txt file where
we stored the full
content of the QuizBank.
So now, you can see that our evals
passed in CircleCI and we were able to store
a formatted version of the output as
you saw it previously in the notebook.
But now, it's in an
HTML file that is easily
retrieved so that you
can look at it later.
The outcomes and descriptions,
decisions and explanations are
similar to what they were before,
but stored in a manner that
anyone on the team can come
and look at them instead of
being local in a notebook.
So, in a production application,
you might share those results
with a colleague to review,
help debug unexpected outcomes.
This feedback loop enables you to
not only address immediate concerns,
but also gives you tools you
can use to implement strategic
updates to your model
and evaluation process.
With this enhanced visibility,
you and your development team
can make data-driven decisions,
streamline the debugging process, and
proactively address potential issues.
Having a holistic understanding of
user interactions, model responses,
and evaluation outcomes is an
important part of building robust and
reliable LLM apps that meet and
exceed your users' expectations.
So, that's the end of this
lesson. Again, in this lesson,
you learned about
hallucinations and how to detect
hallucinations using
model-graded evaluation.
You also learned about
datasets and human evaluation
on top of model-graded evals to ensure
that the quality of the
output you're getting
is exactly what you want for your users.
If you want more details on how
to configure all these things
in CircleCI in your
continuous integration pipeline,
there's an additional notebook
included that shows the core pieces
of that and how to set it up
for your ongoing projects.